<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debug on jaanhio</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/tags/debug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debug on jaanhio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:03:43 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/debug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodejs application CPU profile analysis with Flame Graphs</title>
      <link>/blog/nodejs-flamegraph-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:03:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nodejs-flamegraph-analysis/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;/blog/debugging-nodejs-app&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I shared about my debugging process using various Linux tools and debugger. During the process, I came across the analysis technique using flame graphs and thought it will be interesting to see what information I can get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-flame-graphs&#34;&gt;What are flame graphs?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flame graphs, as the name suggests, are graphs that look like flames because of the shape and color (usually red-yellowish hues). It was invented by Brendan Gregg for the purpose of analyzing performance issue and understand CPU usage quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging high CPU usage and memory leak on Nodejs application</title>
      <link>/blog/debugging-nodejs-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 15:28:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/debugging-nodejs-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;Recently one of our nodejs application (responsible for scraping metrics for external services) running in our EKS cluster was experiencing high CPU usage and memory leak and I was tasked to figure out the root cause.
In this post, I will share my troubleshooting process and interesting stuff I discovered along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all began with an alert notifying us of the application experiencing CPU throttling. Looking at the dashboard, it became apparent that high CPU usage isn&amp;rsquo;t the only issue; it was also experiencing memory leak and oddly high incoming and outgoing traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>